Guide to the Frank Teck papers 1901-1932
Western Washington University, Center for Pacific Northwest Studies
Frank Teck papers
1901-1932
Center for Pacific Northwest Studies Goltz-Murray Building 808 25th St Bellingham, WA 98225-9123 Phone: 360 650 7534 Email: cpnws@wwu.edu
XOE_CPNWS0071teck
Teck, Frank, 1869-1933
.5 linear feet
Frank Teck's materials concern early European exploration and settlement in Whatcom County, as well as later Whatcom County history.
Frank Teck was a local reporter and historian who wrote many articles related to Whatcom County's history and development. Teck was born in Northfield, Minnesota in 1869, attended Morehead College, and then in 1890 headed west eventually making his way to Whatcom County. He made a name for himself as a writer once a series of articles he wrote for Sunset magazine were published. Over his lifetime he wrote for the Seattle Post-intelligencer, Seattle Star, Seattle Times, Union Record, Bellingham American, Herald (Fairhaven), Daily Reveille (Whatcom), Bellingham Evening News, and Anacortes News. He also purchased and ran the Blade newspaper based in Whatcom. In 1899 he published a book of poems entitled Under Western Skies. He died in 1933.
The Frank Teck papers document some of the writings and interests of this newspaper editor, journalist, and local historian. The collections includes articles regarding early European exploration and settlement on the west coast with particular attention paid to the history of Whatcom County, Daniel Jefferson "Dirty Dan" Harris, Robert Morse and the Morse Hardware Company, John Jacob Astor and the development of Astoria, Oregon, and European-American and Native American relations.
The Frank Teck papers are organized in accordance with the following series and subseries arrangement:
Series I: Writing and Research, 1903, 1932 and undated.
Sub-series 1. Whatcom County History Book, undated.
Sub-series 2. Articles, 1932 and undated.
Sub-series 3. Miscellaneous Notes, undated.
Sub-series 4. Newspaper Index Data, undated.
Series II: Correspondence, 1899, 1922-1927.
Series III: Financial Records, 1924.
Series IV: Clippings, 1905-1933.
The collection is open to the public.
These papers originally formed a part of the Michael Sullivan Papers
Donated by Michael Sullivan.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Teck, Frank, 1869-1933 -- Archives; Harris, Daniel Jefferson, 1826-1890.; Morse, R.I. (Robert I.), 1859-1920.; Astor, John Jacob,1763-1848.
Morse Hardware Company.
Whatcom County (Wash.) -- History -- Sources.; Astoria (Or.) -- History -- Sources.
Reporters and reporting -- Washington (State) -- History -- Sources.; Journalists -- Washington (State) -- History -- Sources.; Publishers and publishing -- Washington (State) -- History -- Sources.; Newspaper editors -- Washington (State) -- History -- Sources.; Newspapers -- Washington (State) -- History -- Sources.; Frontier and pioneer Life -- Washington (State) -- Whatcom County -- History -- Sources.; Indians of North America -- Washington (State) -- History -- Sources.
Records (Documents)
Pioneers; Journalism
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Writing and Research, 1903, 1932 and undated.; Series I
  - Whatcom County History Book, undated; Subseries 1
    - Chapter Outlines, undated (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Indians and Indian Wars, undated (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Articles, 1903, 1932 and undated; Subseries 2
    - Robert Morse and Morse Hardware, undated (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Astoria, undated (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Astor Expedition, undated (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Daniel J. Harris, “Dirty Dan,", undated (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Excerpts from Sheriff James Kavanaugh’s diary, undated (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Whatcom Creek Waterway, undated (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Squalicum Creek Waterway Terminal, 1932 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Early History of Bellingham, undated (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Whatcom County’s Early School System, undated (Box-folder 1/11)
    - The Story of Mt Baker (incomplete), undated (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Origin of Mt Baker names, undated (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Early Whatcom County Newspapers, 1903 and undated (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, undated; Subseries 3
    - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box-folder 1/15)
  - Newspaper Index Data, undated., Subseries 4
    - Newspaper Index Data, undated (Box-folder 1/16)
- Correspondence, 1899, 1922-1927.; Series II
  - Correspondence, 1899, 1922-1927 (Box-folder 1/17)
- Financial Records, 1924; Series III
  - Oil and Gas Lease Agreement, 1924 (Box-folder 1/18)
- Clippings, 1905-1933; Series IV
  - Clippings, 1905-1933 (Box-folder 1/19)